His greatest battle begins.
The Amazing Spider-Man 2 is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Marc Webb.
For Peter Parker, life is busy.
Between taking out the bad guys as Spider-Man and spending time with the person he
loves, Gwen Stacy, high school graduation cannot come quickly enough.
Peter has not forgotten about the promise he made to Gwen’s father to protect
her by staying away, but that is a promise he cannot keep.
Things will change for Peter when a new villain, Electro, emerges, an old friend,
Harry Osborn, returns, and Peter uncovers new clues about his past.
Spider-Man / Peter Parker, played by Andrew Garfield.
Gwen Stacy, played by Emma Stone.
Electro / Max Dillon, played by Jamie Foxx.
Green Goblin / Harry Osborn, played by Dane DeHaan.
Donald Menken, played by Colm Feore.
Felicia, played by Felicity Jones.
The Amazing Spider-Man 2 (internationally titled The Amazing Spider-Man 2: Rise of Electro) is a
2014 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics character Spider-Man.
The sequel to The Amazing Spider-Man (2012), it is directed by Marc Webb and written by Alex Kurtzman,
Roberto Orci, and Jeff Pinkner from a story by Kurtzman, Orci, Pinkner and James Vanderbilt.
The film features Andrew Garfield as Peter Parker / Spider-Man, alongside Emma Stone, Jamie Foxx,
Dane DeHaan, Campbell Scott, Embeth Davidtz, Colm Feore, Paul Giamatti and Sally Field.
In the film, Peter Parker tries to protect his girlfriend, Gwen Stacy, as he investigates his parents'
death while also encountering the supervillain Electro and his childhood friend Harry Osborn.
Development of The Amazing Spider-Man 2 began after
the success of The Amazing Spider-Man.
DeHaan, Giamatti, Felicity Jones, and Chris Cooper were
cast between December 2012 and February 2013.
Filming took place in New York City from February to June 2013.
The film was released in 2D, 3D, RealD 3D, and IMAX 3D on May 2, 2014 in the United States, with
two international premieres being held between March 31 and April 10 of that year.
It grossed $716.9 million worldwide, making it the
ninth-highest-grossing film of 2014.
The Amazing Spider-Man film series was originally intended to continue with at least two more
sequels and several spin-offs, most notably films centered on Venom and the Sinister Six.
In February 2015, Sony Pictures and Marvel Studios initiated a deal to share the Spider-Man film rights and reboot the
character within the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU), cancelling future projects in The Amazing Spider-Man series.
Tom Holland succeeded Garfield as Peter Parker / Spider-Man beginning with Captain America: Civil War (2016),
and a new Spider-Man film series set in the MCU began with Spider-Man: Homecoming in 2017.
Both Garfield and Foxx reprised their roles in Spider-Man: No Way Home (2021), which linked
The Amazing Spider-Man films to the MCU using the concept of the multiverse.
The film explores themes of experiment, obsession,
secret identity, superhero, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking.